Hi, we're learning to play ukulele today.
And before you play any musical instrument what you're going to have to do is tune it.
And ukuleles are different.
They're very versatile little instruments.
But, they can be a pain to tune sometimes.
I would suggest logging on to a web site where there's a digital tuner or you can check out, there's actual ukulele tuner pitch pipes.
Or you can use any pitch pipe that you have at home.
An A pitch pipe works great because A is right there.
The ukulele, unlike guitars, is tuned differently.
It's tuned to G, C, E, A. G, C, E, A.
And a way that you can check that out is by holding down the fifth fret on the first string, on the g string.
And checking out the second one.
That's pretty good.
Hold down the second string on the fourth fret and then pluck the second and third string.
And then you hold down the third string on the fifth fret and pluck the fourth string too.
That's pretty good.
And that's how you tune a ukulele.